{
"datos": [
  {
  "pregunta":  "1. What is the supreme law of the land?", 
  "respuesta":  "The Constitution.The Bible.Robinson Crusoe", 
  "correcta": "The Constitution",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track01.mp3" 
  },
  {
  "pregunta":  "2. What does the Constitution do?", 
  "respuesta":  "Budget the government.Protects basic rights of Americans", 
  "correcta": "Protects basic rights of Americans",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track02.mp3" 
  },
  {
  "pregunta": "3. The idea of self-government is in the first three words of the Constitution. What are these words?",
  "respuesta":  "Me the President.We the People", 
  "correcta": "We the People",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track03.mp3" 
  },
  {
  "pregunta": "4. What is an amendment?", 
  "respuesta":  "A fix in the Goverment.A change to the Constitution.A mistake in the Constitution", 
  "correcta": "A change to the Constitution",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track04.mp3" 
  },
  {
  "pregunta": "5. What do we call the first ten amendments to the Constitution?", 
  "respuesta":  "The Rights of the People.The Right things.The Bill of Rights", 
  "correcta": "The Bill of Rights",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track05.mp3" 
  },
{
  "pregunta": "6. What is one right or freedom from the First Amendment?", 
  "respuesta":  "Church.Citizenship.Speech", 
  "correcta": "Speech",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track06.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "7. How many amendments does the Constitution have?", 
  "respuesta":  "seven(7).twenty-seven(27).twenty(20).thirty-seven(37)", 
  "correcta": "twenty-seven(27)",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track07.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "8. What did the Declaration of Independence do?", 
  "respuesta":  "Announced our independence (from Great Britain).Declared our Constitution.Said that the United States is free (from the Black Death)", 
  "correcta": "Announced our independence (from Great Britain)",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track08.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "9. What are two rights in the Declaration of Independence?", 
  "respuesta":  "Liberty and Progress.Life and pursuit of happiness", 
  "correcta": "Life and pursuit of happiness",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track09.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "10. What is freedom of religion?", 
  "respuesta":  "You can practice any religion, or not practice a religion.You can be a chatolic or a baptist", 
  "correcta": "You can practice any religion, or not practice a religion",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track10.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "11. What is the economic system in the United States?", 
  "respuesta":  "Capitalist economy.Socialist economy", 
  "correcta": "Capitalist economy",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track11.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "12. What is the “rule of law”?", 
  "respuesta":  "Everyone knows the law.Leaders must discuss about the law.Government does not have to obey the law.No one is above the law", 
  "correcta": "No one is above the law",
  "sonido":  "sounds/Track12.mp3" 
},
{
  "pregunta": "13. Name one branch or part of the government",
  "respuesta": "Health.Executive.Republican party",
  "correcta": "Executive",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track13.mp3"
},
{
  "pregunta": "14. What stops one branch of government from becoming too powerful ?",
  "respuesta": "Patriotism.The President.Separation of Powers",
  "correcta": "Separation of Powers",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track14.mp3"
},
{
  "pregunta": "15. Who is in charge of the executive branch ?",
  "respuesta": "The Vice President.The President.The Speaker of the House",
  "correcta": "The President",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track15.mp3"
},
{
  "pregunta": "16. Who makes federal laws? ",
  "respuesta": "Congress.The President.The Army",
  "correcta": "Congress",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track16.mp3"
},
{
  "pregunta": "17. What are the two parts of the U.S. Congress?",
  "respuesta": "The President and the Senate.The Senate and House of Representatives.The Goverment and the Army",
  "correcta": "The Senate and House of Representatives",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track17.mp3"
},
{
  "pregunta": "18. How many U.S. Senators are there?",
  "respuesta": "One hundred (100).Four hundred thirty-five (435)",
  "correcta": "One hundred (100)",
  "sonido": "sounds/Track18.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "19. We elect a U.S. Senator for how many years?",
  "correcta": "Six (6)",
"respuesta": "Four (4).Six (6)",
"sonido": "sounds/Track19.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "20. Who is one of your state’s U.S. Senators now?",
  "correcta": "Marco Rubio",
"respuesta": "Ron D'Santis.Marco Rubio.Mark Anthony",
"sonido": "sounds/Track20.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "21. The House of Representatives has how many voting members?",
  "correcta": "Four hundred thirty-five (435)",
"respuesta": "One hundred (100).Four hundred thirty-five (435)",
"sonido": "sounds/Track21.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "22. We elect a U.S. Representative for how many years?",
  "correcta": "Two (2)",
"respuesta": "Two (2).Four (4)",
"sonido": "sounds/Track22.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "23. Name your U.S. Representative",
  "correcta": "Darren Soto",
"respuesta": "Darren Soto.Mario Diaz Balart",
"sonido": "sounds/Track23.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "24. Who does a U.S. Senator represent? ",
  "correcta": "All people of the state",
"respuesta": "Goverment people.All people of the state",
"sonido": "sounds/Track24.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "25. Why do some states have more Representatives than other states?",
  "correcta": "Because some states have more people",
"respuesta": "Because of the state’s economy.Because they have more schools.Because some states have more people",
"sonido": "sounds/Track25.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "26. We elect a President for how many years? ",
  "correcta": "Four (4)",
"respuesta": "Four (4).Forty (4o).Five (5)",
"sonido": "sounds/Track26.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "27. In what month do we vote for President?",
  "correcta": "November",
"respuesta": "September.November.January",
"sonido": "sounds/Track27.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "28. What is the name of the President of the United States now?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track28.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "29. What is the name of the Vice President of the United States now?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track29.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "30. If the President can no longer serve, who becomes President?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The Vice President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track30.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "31. If both the President and the Vice President can no longer serve, who becomes President? ",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The Speaker of the House",
"sonido": "sounds/Track31.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "32. Who is the Commander in Chief of the military?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track32.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "33. Who signs bills to become laws? ",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track33.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "34. Who vetoes bills?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track34.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "35. What does the President’s Cabinet do?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "Advises the President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track35.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "36. What are two Cabinet-level positions?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "- Secretary of Agriculture- Secretary of Commerce- Secretary of Defense- Secretary of Education- Secretary of Energy- Secretary of Health and Human Services- Secretary of Homeland Security- Secretary of Housing and Urban Development- Secretary of the Interior- Secretary of Labor- Secretary of State- Secretary of Transportation- Secretary of the Treasury- Secretary of Veterans Affairs- Attorney General- Vice President",
"sonido": "sounds/Track36.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "37. What does the judicial branch do?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "Reviews laws  - Explains laws  - Resolves disputes (disagreements)  - Decides if a law goes against the Constitution",
"sonido": "sounds/Track37.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "38. What is the highest court in the United States?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "The Supreme Court",
"sonido": "sounds/Track38.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "39. How many justices are on the Supreme Court?  ",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track39.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "40. Who is the Chief Justice of the United States now?  ",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track40.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "41. Under our Constitution, some powers belong to the federal government.  What is one power of the federal government?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "- To print money  - To declare war  - To create an army  - To make treaties",
"sonido": "sounds/Track41.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "42. Under our Constitution, some powers belong to the states.  What is one power of the states?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "- Provide schooling and education  - Provide protection(police)  - Provide safety(fire departments)  - Give a driver’s license  - Approve zoning and land use",
"sonido": "sounds/Track42.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "43. Who is the Governor of your state now?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track43.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "44. What is the capital of your state?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "Talahassee",
"sonido": "sounds/Track44.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "45. What are the two major political parties in the United States?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "Democratic and Republican",
"sonido": "sounds/Track45.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "46. What is the political party of the President now?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track46.mp3"
},
{
"pregunta": "47. What is the name of the Speaker of the House of Representatives now?",
  "correcta": "",
"respuesta": "n/a",
"sonido": "sounds/Track47.mp3"
}
]}

    